<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on userrepository blog</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/</link><description>userrepository blog (Posts)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New look</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/new-look/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/new-look/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.userrepository.eu/new-look/new-look.png" alt="Growing number of packages">
&lt;small>Screenshot by me, under the &lt;em>Creative Commons (&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/">CC-BY-SA-4.0&lt;/a>)&lt;/em> license&lt;/small>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The repository got a makeover. Well, the content the webserver displays got a makeover. Instead of showing just a plain open directory, the visitors will now see a more good-looking HTML page with the list of the packages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This change will have no impact on how you install the packages on your computers. That will remain as it always was: at a &lt;em>pacman -Syu %package_name%&lt;/em> away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To make it smooth on the eyes, I chose the Catppuccin colour scheme. This was the perfect excuse I was looking to use it. I find it vastly enjoyable to look at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can take a look at it on &lt;a href="https://github.com/catppuccin/catppuccin">Github&lt;/a> and, if you&amp;rsquo;d like, use it on any of the supported applications. Each one has its own dedicated repository.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you believe in Userrepository, please &lt;a href="https://fosshost.org/donate">donate to Fosshost&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s thanks to them that this repository keeps running. By donating, you&amp;rsquo;ll also support the broader FOSS community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting close to the 1500 packages</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/almost-1500-packages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/almost-1500-packages/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.userrepository.eu/almost-1500-packages/jungwoo-hong-cYUMaCqMYvI-unsplash.jpg" alt="Growing number of packages">
&lt;small>Image by Jungwoo Hong and downloaded from &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/cYUMaCqMYvI">Unsplash&lt;/a>&lt;/small>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the last blog post, on the 29&lt;sup>th&lt;/sup> of October 2021, the number of packages has been steadily increasing. At the time of writing, the total number is an impressive 1349. The new packages range from utilities to download videos from Youtube, compression and decompression applications, window switchers for Sway, typefaces, etc. You name the type of software, and it&amp;rsquo;s probably there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The repository growth in terms of package numbers makes me happy and excited! Ever since I opened it up to the general public, I intended for it to have a lot of different helpful software for the most significant number of users possible. Getting close to the 1500 packages demonstrates the goal has been reached. But that won&amp;rsquo;t stop me from adding as many new packages as possible if I consider them valuable to the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having an ever-increasing number of packages means a possible upsurge in the bandwidth. Cloudflare only lets users in the free tier see, at most, the last 30 days, but I remember it showing a little more than 40GB served per month around December. However, in the previous 30 days, it has pumped 61.11GB of data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.userrepository.eu/almost-1500-packages/last-30-days-total-data-stats.png" alt="Data served in the last 30 days">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These numbers are nowhere near the &lt;a href="https://fosshost.org/news/mirror-stats">23TB of data&lt;/a> Fosshost delivered in just one week with its mirror service. I wish they were. I&amp;rsquo;m still stunned by those Fosshost numbers, and I was the one who wrote the announcement! Nonetheless, I am very proud of what I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished so far. I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to work towards growing the number of packages and keeping Userrepository beneficial to the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you believe in Userrepository, as I do, please &lt;a href="https://fosshost.org/donate">donate to Fosshost&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s thanks to them that this software repository keeps running. When things got nasty due to Covid-19 and being diagnosed with fibromyalgia, Fosshost provided me with a VM for free to this day! And by donating to them, you&amp;rsquo;ll also be supporting the broader FOSS community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>More than 1000 packages available</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/more-than-1000-packages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/more-than-1000-packages/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the 29th of October, 2021, userrepository hit the 1000 packages mark and is now offering, at the time of this writing, 1009 packages. I intended to accomplish this before the end of the year and I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I made it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Changes to the build process</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/partial-builds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/partial-builds/</guid><description>&lt;p>Until a few days ago, all the packages available at userrepository.eu were built in batch. Given the number of packages is over 800, it took more than 10 hours (yes, 10 hours) to complete each daily full build.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, a new option in the build script only builds the updated packages. Not only that, all &lt;code>*-git&lt;/code> packages are also built with this new option. I made this decision because the lack of version updates on these AUR packages doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean there isn&amp;rsquo;t an update to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The script runs every 6 hours and takes about 4h30m to complete.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To finish this blog post, a thank you note to &lt;a href="https://fosshost.org">Fosshost&lt;/a> for kindly increasing the resources on the VM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Featured package: emptty-git</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/featured-package-emptty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/featured-package-emptty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, reader. Welcome to the first blog post featuring a package available for installation at the &lt;a href="https://userrepository.eu">repository&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As stated in the &lt;a href="https://userrepository.eu/post/hello-world">previous post&lt;/a>, I will occasionally highlight a package I feel it brings value to the users. My first choice is &lt;a href="https://github.com/tvrzna/emptty">&lt;code>emptty-git&lt;/code>&lt;/a>, a really fast and simple Display Manager that runs on a TTY.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This CLI Display Manager is blazing fast and offers a few configuration options. One of these options and my personal favorite is setting the MOTD, like the one you can see in the next section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also choose the TTY where it will run, set auto login, create &lt;a href="https://github.com/tvrzna/emptty/blob/master/SAMPLES.md#custom-sessions">custom sessions&lt;/a> just for emptty and a couple customization options you can check over at &lt;a href="https://github.com/tvrzna/emptty">Github&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="screenshot">Screenshot&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../featured-posts/emptty.jpg" alt="second screenshot">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to-install">How to install&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo pacman -Syu emptty-git&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.userrepository.eu/post/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am delighted to &lt;strong>finally&lt;/strong> announce the availability of the &lt;strong>userrepository blog&lt;/strong>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Launching a blog for the repository was something I was considering for over six months. However, due to personal circumstances and, well, life, the idea got put in a drawer. That was only until the 29th of June 2021, when I started dabbling with static site generators.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-toolkit">The toolkit&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After a bit of fussing, I chose &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> as the generator.&lt;/strong> Hugo was my choice as the generator because I was already familiar with it, and it feels accessible for a non-dev like me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://github.com/mitrichius/hugo-theme-anubis">Anubis&lt;/a> was my theme choice to build upon my own.&lt;/strong> The original theme is under the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Mitrichius/hugo-theme-anubis/blob/master/LICENSE">MIT license&lt;/a> and so is my fork of Anubis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The source code for this blog is available at &lt;a href="https://github.com/brunomiguel/userrepository-blog">Github&lt;/a>. You are welcome to fork it, make PRs and report issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-the-blog-will-cover">What the blog will cover&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I will &lt;strong>write about the occasional update about the repo&lt;/strong>. These blog posts can include, among other subjects, new packages, changes to the build system, scheduled reboots, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Featured packages&lt;/strong> will be another type of blog post published. I will highlight an available package on the repo that I feel will bring value to its users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Comments about changes to / news regarding &lt;a href="https://archlinux.org/">Arch Linux&lt;/a>, quick tips and screenshots for the VM running the repository will also be found on the occasion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="screenshots">Screenshots&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Speaking of VM screenshots, here are two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../hello-world/vm1.jpg">&lt;img src="../../hello-world/vm1.jpg" alt="first screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../hello-world/vm2.jpg">&lt;img src="../../hello-world/vm2.jpg" alt="second screenshot">&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="enable-the-repository">Enable the repository&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Create the file &lt;mark>&lt;code>/etc/pacman.d/userrepository&lt;/code>&lt;/mark> and add:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-ini" data-lang="ini">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Server&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">https://userrepository.eu&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">SigLevel&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">Optional TrustAll&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Now, edit &lt;mark>&lt;code>/etc/pacman.conf&lt;/code>&lt;/mark> and put in it the following content:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-ini" data-lang="ini">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">[userrepository]&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Include&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">/etc/pacman.d/userrepository&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The last step is running pacman:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>sudo pacman -Syu&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>